https://www.toxpath.org/privacy_policy.asp

703-438-7508
The Society of Toxicologic Pathology Policies and Disclaimers
Home / The Society of Toxicologic Pathology Policies and Disclaimers
Adopted May 15, 2019
The Society of Toxicologic Pathology (“STP”) is a professional society dedicated to the promotion of human, animal, and environmental health through enhanced understanding and practice of toxicologic pathology. It is imperative that STP members recognize that they are bound by ethical values and principles, both personal and professional, based on honesty, integrity, and accountability. Furthermore, the STP encourages members to uphold all laws, regulations, and other safety and ethical standards related to the welfare of colleagues and working with animals in research. A member who fails to maintain these standards or otherwise exhibits conduct deemed detrimental to the Society, as defined in Article X of the STP Bylaws – Disciplinary Action and Appeals, may be censured, suspended, expelled, or placed on probation.
Non-Discrimination and Anti-Harassment Policy
Adopted May 28, 2019
The Society of Toxicologic Pathology (“STP”) is committed to an environment in which all participants in STP activities are treated with respect and dignity and able to enjoy an environment free from all forms of discrimination, harassment and retaliation. This policy extends to all STP members, management staff, and participants in STP activities and business relationships.
As a professional society, the STP is committed to providing an atmosphere that encourages the free expression and exchange of scientific ideas. To achieve that goal, the STP is dedicated to the philosophy of equality of opportunity and treatment of all its members, management staff, and participants in STP activities, regardless of gender, gender identity or expression, race, color, national or ethnic origin, religion or religious belief, age, marital status, sexual orientation, disability, veteran status or any other legally protected characteristic.
Each individual has the right to participate in STP activities and, in the case of STP’s management staff, work in a professional atmosphere that promotes equal employment opportunities and prohibits unlawful discriminatory practices, including unlawful harassment, retaliation and other forms of inappropriate and/or offensive conduct. Therefore, the STP expects that all relationships among persons, including STP members, management staff, and participants in STP activities and business relationships will be business-like and free of bias, prejudice and harassment.
The STP’s Executive Committee and management company will make every reasonable effort to ensure that all concerned are familiar with these policies and are aware that any complaint in potential violation of such policies will be investigated and resolved appropriately.
Any STP member, management staff or participant in STP activities who has questions or concerns about these policies should consult with the STP Executive Director or President.
These policies should not, and may not, be used as a basis for excluding or separating individuals of a particular gender, race, color, national or ethnic origin, religion or religious belief, age, marital status, sexual orientation, disability, veteran status or any other protected characteristic, from participating in any STP activities or programs. The bylaws and policies of the STP strictly prohibit disparate treatment on the basis of gender or any other legally protected characteristic with regard to participation in STP’s governance, programs, meetings and other Society activities. The prohibitions against harassment, discrimination and retaliation are intended to complement and further those policies, not to form the basis of an exception to them.
Equal employment opportunity
It is the policy of the STP to ensure equal opportunity to participate as an STP officer, councilor, volunteer, member, contractor, exhibitor, guest, meeting or attendee without fear of discrimination or harassment on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, age, disability, marital status, citizenship, national origin, genetic information, or any other characteristic protected by law. The STP prohibits any such discrimination or harassment.
Behavioral Expectations of STP
STP members, management staff, and participants in STP activities are expected to exhibit respectful and professional behavior at all times in all venues, including ancillary events and unofficial social gatherings. To help achieve this goal, consider the following:
exercise consideration and respect in your speech and actions;
be mindful of your surroundings and of your fellow participants;
alert STP leaders or management staff if you notice a dangerous situation, someone in distress, or potential violations of this policy, even if they seem inconsequential.
Behaviors that are deemed unacceptable by the STP include, but are not limited to:
intimidating, harassing, abusive, discriminatory, derogatory or demeaning speech or actions by any participant in STP activities, at all related events and in communications carried out in the context of STP activities;
offensive, degrading, humiliating, harmful, or prejudicial verbal or written comments, gestures, or visual images related to gender, sexual orientation, ethnicity, religion, disability, age, appearance, or other legally protected characteristics;
unwelcome and/or uninvited attention or contact; including, but not limited to, unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or other verbal/physical conduct of a sexual nature;
inappropriate or gratuitous use of nudity, sexual images, or stereotyped images including the use of an activity-related communication channel to display or distribute sexually explicit or otherwise offensive or discriminatory images or messages;
deliberate intimidation, stalking or following, via physical, social, or electronic means;
harassing photography or recording;
sustained disruption of talks or other events;
physical assault (including unwelcome touch or groping);
real or implied threat of physical harm;
real or implied threat of professional or financial damage or harm.
Retaliation
The STP strongly encourages reporting of all potential incidents of discrimination or harassment. It is the policy of the STP to promptly and thoroughly investigate such reports. The STP prohibits retaliation against any individual who reports discrimination or harassment or participates in an investigation of such reports.
Sexual harassment
Sexual harassment constitutes discrimination and is illegal under federal, state and local laws. For the purposes of this policy, “sexual harassment” is defined as unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors and other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature, including when such conduct has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with an individual’s performance or work as a volunteer or creating an intimidating, hostile or offensive work or volunteer activity environment.
Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 recognizes two types of sexual harassment: a) quid pro quo and b) hostile work or volunteer environment. Sexual harassment may include a range of subtle and not-so-subtle behaviors and may involve individuals of the same or different gender. Depending on the circumstances, these behaviors may include unwanted sexual advances or requests for sexual favors; sexual jokes and innuendo; verbal abuse of a sexual nature; commentary about an individual’s body, sexual prowess or sexual deficiencies; leering, whistling or touching; insulting or obscene comments or gestures; display in the workplace or at association events or meetings of sexually suggestive objects or pictures; and other physical, verbal or visual conduct of a sexual nature.
Harassment
Harassment on the basis of any other legally protected characteristic is also strictly prohibited. Under this policy, harassment includes verbal, written or physical conduct that denigrates or shows hostility or aversion toward an individual because of his or her race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, national origin, age, disability, marital status, citizenship, genetic information, or any other characteristic protected by law, or that of his or her relatives, friends or associates, and that: a) has the purpose or effect of creating an intimidating, hostile or offensive work or volunteer environment, b) has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with an individual’s work or volunteer performance, or c) otherwise adversely affects an individual’s employment or volunteer opportunities.
Harassing conduct includes epithets, slurs or negative stereotyping; threatening, intimidating or hostile acts; denigrating jokes; and written or graphic material that denigrates or shows hostility or aversion toward an individual or group that is placed on walls or elsewhere at an STP event or meeting or using STP’s equipment by e-mail, phone (including voice messages), text messages, social networking sites or apps or other means.
Individuals and Conduct Covered
These policies apply to all STP members, management staff, and participants in STP activities and business relationships. Conduct prohibited by these policies is unacceptable in the STP’s business, governance, volunteer, or meeting environments.
Reporting Harassment, Discrimination, or Retaliation
The STP strongly encourages reporting of all perceived incidents of discrimination, harassment, or retaliation, regardless of the offender’s identity or position. Individuals who believe that they have been the victim of such conduct should discuss their concerns with the STP Executive Director and/or the management company Human Resources Director or report them via the Whistleblower hotline.
To anonymously report suspected criminal activity or illegal or unethical conduct by an
STP member, management staff, or participant in any STP activity or business relationship,
call the Navex toll-free fraud hotline at 800-826-6762.
In addition, the STP encourages individuals who believe they are being subjected to such conduct to promptly advise the offender that his or her behavior is unwelcome and to request that it be discontinued. Often this action alone will resolve the problem. The STP recognizes, however, that an individual may prefer to pursue the matter through complaint procedures.
Complaint Procedure
Individuals who believe they have been the victims of conduct prohibited by this policy or believe they have witnessed such conduct should report and discuss their concerns with the STP Executive Director and/or the management company Human Resources Director. Upon a thorough investigation and review of the facts, the Executive Director and management company Human Resources Director may refer the matter to the STP Executive Committee and/or management company Human Resources Director for further consideration and action.
The STP encourages the prompt reporting of complaints or concerns so that rapid and constructive action can be taken before relationships become irreparably strained. Therefore, while no fixed reporting period has been established, early reporting and intervention have proven to be the most effective method of resolving actual or perceived incidents of harassment.
Any reported allegations of harassment, discrimination, or retaliation will be investigated promptly by authorized STP representatives. The investigation may include individual interviews with the parties involved and, where necessary, with individuals who may have observed the alleged conduct or may have other relevant knowledge.
The STP will endeavor to maintain confidentiality throughout the investigatory process to the extent consistent with adequate investigation and appropriate corrective action.
Retaliation against an individual for reporting harassment or discrimination or for participating in an investigation of a claim of harassment or discrimination is a serious violation of this policy and, like harassment or discrimination itself, will be subject to disciplinary action. Acts of retaliation should be reported immediately and will be promptly investigated and addressed.
Misconduct constituting harassment, discrimination or retaliation will be dealt with appropriately. Responsive action may include, for example, suspension or termination of STP membership, removal from office in the case of an STP officer or councilor, or removal from a volunteer leadership position. In the case of a member of STP’s management staff, that may include disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment. The decision of the Executive Committee on such matters will be final.
False and malicious complaints of harassment, discrimination, or retaliation (as opposed to complaints that, even if erroneous, are made in good faith) may be the subject of appropriate disciplinary action, including, but not limited to, suspension or termination of membership, removal from office in the case of an STP officer or councilor, or removal from a volunteer leadership position. In the case of a member of the STP’s management staff, such response may include disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment.
Privacy Policy and Disclaimers
Adopted May 25, 2018
The Society of Toxicologic Pathology (“STP”) is committed to honoring the privacy of our members and those who visit our website and engage in our services. The Privacy Policy governs how we collect, store, and use information about our members, partners, and website visitors. It will be continuously reexamined in light of new technologies, new business practices, and the changing needs of our visitors. This privacy policy applies to all personal data processed by full-time and part-time employees, volunteers when acting on behalf of STP and all business processes conducted by STP.
When you participate in, access, or sign up for membership or any of STP’s events, services, activities, online content, webinars, online communities, or create an online account, STP may receive personal information from you. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, telephone numbers, log-in password, location information, gender, date of birth, educational information, purchasing or payment information, subscription preferences, as well as any additional information you upload or provide to us, in addition to information collected about your use of STP services.
Please note that sometimes we will require you to provide additional personal information, including sensitive personal information (e.g., social security numbers from US citizens who receive awards or grants from STP), typically to comply with laws and regulations. When we do this, we will provide further information about why we are collecting your information and how we will use it.
For General Users
STP does not collect any personal identifying information from users just browsing our website. Our server recognizes your domain name and the pages that you visit. These data are gathered in an aggregate manner for quality control, statistical purposes, and improvement of our site. This information is never forwarded to any third parties.
For STP Members, Meeting Registrants, and other Customers
Personal information collected from you is used to respond to your inquiries and to fulfill a service such as meeting registration, abstract submittal, or dues renewal. To gain access to the member-restricted information, members are asked to provide their email address and password. Information provided on our Membership Application(s) is used internally to determine the eligibility of membership and will not be shared with a third party.
How Your Information is Used
STP uses this information to respond to your requests, enhance its products and services, and to improve your experience, making the organization better for all who engage with STP.
Demographic information is specifically used for the purpose of monitoring or improving the use of and satisfaction with our services. STP ensures the security and privacy of any personally identifiable information that we collect.
STP will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collect it unless we reasonably believe that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. We will notify you prior to any additional processing.
Legal Basis for Using Your Information
STP will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. We may use your personal data in order to perform the contract we entered into with you. If you failed to provide personal data required to perform the contract, we may not be able to perform the contract and we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us. We will notify you if this is the case at the time.
STP may use your personal data based on your consent. By providing STP your personal information, you are actively agreeing to interact with us, though STP membership and/or other events and services, and giving us consent to use your personal data. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us. Please remember that withdrawing your consent does not remove the legal basis to use your information to perform the contract where applicable.
How Long Your Information is Stored
Per our record retention policy, STP maintains this information for as long as a member or other customer/partner is actively engaged with the society and for four years after their last interaction, to ensure that those interested in STP services are provided the latest information. STP also maintains key accounting information for tax purposes for seven years after closure.
Disclosure to Third Parties
STP makes member contact and demographic information available through the STP website, the ToxPathNet member network, and the Membership Directory online only to other members using the website. STP uses your email address to respond to your request(s) and to relay membership communication such as Officer and Bylaws Ballots, and important membership correspondence. Periodically, STP may share personally identifiable information with organizations that we believe might have a product or service of interest to you. Limited data provided to third parties include name, affiliation, and business address. Your email, telephone, and fax numbers will not be disclosed to third parties.
At any time, you may view and/or update your registered information by accessing your Membership Profile. Alternatively, users may contact STP Headquarters or call 703.438.7508. You may update your online profile at any time to indicate that you do not want us to share your mailing information with third parties or to update your subscription preferences.
Responses to Legal Requests
STP reserves the right to share your information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law. STP will ensure proper communication with regulatory authorities to ensure privacy.
Do We Employ Cookies?
STP uses ‘Authentication Cookies’ used by web servers to know whether the user is logged in or not, and which account they are logged in with. Without such a mechanism, the site would not know whether to send a page containing sensitive information, or require the user to authenticate themselves by logging in. Cookies are generated by our website to provide you with a personalized and enhanced online experience. These cookies make your navigation through our sites easier by saving your passwords, preferences, and member profile information. Cookies also show how visitors use our site and enable us to make improvements based on actual visitor traffic patterns. The use of cookies in this manner is an association industry standard. Nonetheless, you can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website may become inaccessible or not function properly.
How can I control my information?
You can control the information we have about you and how we use it in several ways:
If you are a registered user, you can review, revise, and correct the personal data that you have provided to STP via your STP ToxPathNet account;
If you have received an unwanted email, use the unsubscribe method provided in our various communications and/or manage your subscription preferences online; and
If you no longer wish to interact with STP and want your personal information deleted, you can make a request by contacting us by email or as outlined below. STP will delete your personal information and maintain your participation information in an anonymous fashion, so that any data we hold about how you have interacted with STP in the past will be made anonymous.
International Transfer
STP is headquartered in the United States and your personal data may be transferred to the United States or other locations where privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. For the European Union users, the European Commission has approved the use of model contract clauses as a means of ensuring adequate protection when transferring data outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By incorporating model contract clauses into a contract between STP and the third-party processors that STP engages, your information can be protected when transferred outside of the EEA to countries which have not been deemed by the European Commission to adequately protect personal data, including the United States.
European Union Privacy Rights
Under the General Data Protection Regulation (also known as GDPR), if you are an individual protected by the GDPR, you have the following rights:
Access: you may receive information about our processing of your personal data and a copy of your personal data.
Correct: you may request us to update or correct inaccurate data we have about you. You can also do this by accessing your information as described above.
Delete: you may ask us to delete your personal information. See above for more detail.
Opt-out: you may change your subscription setting at any time and stop receiving any direct marketing communications as described above.
Transfer: you may ask us to transfer your personal data in a machine-readable format to a third party of your choice.
Restrict: you may ask us to restrict the processing of your personal information under certain circumstances.
Object: you may object to our reliance on our legitimate interest as the basis of our processing if you believe it impacts your fundamental rights and freedoms.
Complain: you have a right to submit a complaint to the supervisory authority in the Member State in which you are located. The list of Data Protection authorities and their contact information are available on the European Commission’s website.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights above, please contact us by email at STP Headquarters or call 703-438-7508.
Disclaimers
International Intellectual Property and Copyright laws protect all materials contained on the STP website. ‘Material’ includes all text, graphics, icons, photographs, software, audio, and video. Permission is granted to download, copy, or print material for personal, instructional, or noncommercial use.
Information contained on our website does not necessarily represent the views or opinions of the Society of Toxicologic Pathology. Information found on the STP website should not be relied on as medical, legal, business, or tax advice.
The STP website provides hyperlinks to external sites for the convenience of our visitors. Such a hyperlink doesn’t imply that the STP endorses the content or operation of external sites. You are solely responsible for how you use any external site linked from this website.
The laws of the State of Virginia and the United States of America apply, no matter where this website is viewed. Any suits filed against STP must be filed in the state of Virginia.
This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time, and you are urged to review it periodically. Use of this website constitutes agreement to the Policy that is posted at the time of use.
Organizations with Conflicting Missions
The very foundation of the Society is to be an international leader for improvement of human, animal, and environmental health using an interdisciplinary scientific approach based in pathology and toxicology. To this end, the Society reserves the right to not (1) accept financial support from, (2) provide, or (3) otherwise collaborate with any organization whose goals, objectives, or past actions are deemed counterproductive to those of the Society of Toxicologic Pathology.
How to Contact STP and Provide Feedback
Our goal is to protect your privacy. To comment on or help us to improve this privacy policy, contact us by email at STP Headquarters or call 703-438-7508.
Whistleblower Policy
Adopted May 28, 2019
The Society of Toxicologic Pathology (“STP”) requires its members, participants in STP activities, and management staff to observe the highest standards of business and personal ethics in the conduct of their duties and responsibilities on behalf of the STP. As representatives of the STP, STP members must carry out their duties and responsibilities with integrity and comply with all applicable laws and regulations. This Policy sets forth the processes by which STP members and others outlined above may report potential unethical conduct in the context of STP-related functions.
Reporting Responsibility
This Whistleblower Policy is intended to encourage and enable all STP members, participants in STP activities, and management staff to raise serious concerns so that the STP can address inappropriate, unethical, or illegal conduct and actions. It is the responsibility of all those associated with the STP, including its members, participants in STP activities, and management staff to report concerns about violations of the STP’s Ethics Policy or suspected violations of law or regulations that govern and apply to STP’s governance, finances, and operations.
No Retaliation
It is contrary to the values and policies of the STP to retaliate against an STP member or management staff member who in good faith reports a potential violation of the Ethics Policy or the law, including complaints of discrimination, harassment, fraud, or regulations governing STP operations. An STP member or management staff member who retaliates against someone who has reported a violation in good faith will be subject to discipline, up to and including termination of employment in the case of management staff.
Reporting Procedure
The STP and its management company have an open-door policy and encourage STP members, participants in STP activities, and management staff to share their questions or concerns, suggestions, or complaints either in person or in writing with either the STP Executive Director or the management company Human Resources Director (in the case of personnel issues) or to the STP Executive Director or STP Secretary-Treasurer in the case of financial or management concerns. In the event of concerns or a complaint addressed to quality of service or misuse of STP property, such complaint should be directed to the STP President. All reported complaints will be investigated.
In addition to the above-described reporting procedures, the following STP Whistleblower Protection message is located at the bottom of the STP website homepage:
To anonymously report suspected criminal activity or illegal or unethical conduct by an STP member, management staff, or participant in any STP activity or STP business relationship, call the Navex toll-free fraud hotline at 800-826-6762.
Compliance Officer
The STP’s Executive Director is primarily charged with carrying out this policy and is responsible for ensuring that all complaints about unethical or illegal conduct are investigated and resolved. The Executive Director will advise the STP Executive Committee of all complaints and their resolution and report at least annually to the STP Executive Committee, including the Secretary-Treasurer on compliance activity relating to accounting or alleged financial improprieties.
Accounting and Auditing Matters
The STP’s Executive Director shall immediately notify the Secretary-Treasurer and STP Executive Committee of any concerns or complaint regarding corporate accounting practices, internal controls, or auditing and work with the same until the matter is resolved.
Acting in Good Faith
Any person making a complaint, orally or in writing, concerning a potential violation must be acting in good faith and have reasonable grounds for believing the information disclosed indicates a violation. Any allegations that prove not to be substantiated and which prove to have been made maliciously, recklessly, or knowingly to be false will be viewed as a serious disciplinary offense and addressed by the Executive Committee. In the case of STP’s management company staff, the making of a malicious or knowingly false report may result in disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment.
Confidentiality
Violations or suspected violations may be submitted on a confidential basis by the complainant. Reports of violations or suspected violations will be kept confidential to the extent possible, consistent with the need to conduct an adequate investigation.
Handling of Reported Violations
The STP’s Executive Director will notify the person who submitted the complaint and acknowledge receipt of the reported potential violation. All reports will be promptly investigated and appropriate corrective action will be taken if warranted by the investigation.
Working with Animals (3Rs) Policy
Adopted May 28, 2019
The Society of Toxicologic Pathology (“STP”) is a professional society dedicated to the promotion of human, animal, and environmental health through enhanced understanding and practice of toxicologic pathology. The STP is committed to advancing the science of toxicologic pathology as a means of protecting the health and safety of both people and animals and for the preservation of our environment. The STP recognizes that working with animals in research is a necessary and critical component in pursuit of this commitment. However, it is the position of the STP that when working with animals, careful consideration should be given to selection of the appropriate animal model and study design to address the purpose of the study. In all cases, the STP seeks to promote the best possible science and the humane treatment of animals used to advance our understanding of human and animal risk and safety assessment.
Animals should be maintained and treated in a proper and humane manner and in full conformance with all governing regulations and guidelines. The STP subscribes to the concept of the 3R’s (refinement, reduction, and replacement) and supports research to enhance that concept where scientifically valid.
The STP further encourages all members to uphold the Society of Toxicologic Pathology Ethics Policy wherein it states that STP members recognize that they are bound by ethical values and principles, both personal and professional, based on honesty, integrity, and accountability. Furthermore, the STP encourages members to uphold all laws, regulations, and other safety and ethical standards related to the welfare of colleagues and working with animals in research.
Principles on Working with Animals in Toxicologic Pathology
The STP endorses and adopts the following guidelines and principles:
International Guiding Principles for Biomedical Research Involving Animals of the Council for International Organizations of Medical Sciences of the World Health Organization.
US Government Principles for the Utilization and Care of Vertebrate Animals Used in Testing, Research and Training of the US Public Health Service.
Society of Toxicology: Position Statement Regarding the Use of Animals in Toxicology & Animals in Research Public Policy Statement.
American College of Toxicology: Policy Statement on the Use of Animals in Toxicology.
All personnel involved in studies working with animals shall be knowledgeable and skilled in the procedures to be used and trained in the humane care and use of animals in compliance with all applicable animal welfare laws. Studies should be designed to attain maximum information, including biological and toxicological data, working with the least number of animals with due regard for minimizing pain or distress. For example, pilot studies conducted with small numbers of animals may eliminate the need for further studies or result in information leading to optimized study designs requiring fewer animal numbers.
Primary responsibility for the care and handling of animals shall be under the direction of a veterinarian knowledgeable in the area. The veterinarian shall intervene in a study to provide appropriate treatment to minimize pain and discomfort. When surgical procedures are necessary, the investigator and veterinarian shall work together to assure appropriate technique is used and that anesthetics and postoperative analgesia are appropriate for the species being worked with in the study. When meaningful scientific data can no longer be obtained from an animal, euthanasia, appropriate for the species, shall be implemented according to current guidelines.
Protocols involving working with animals should be reviewed by a committee, i.e., Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC), to assure compliance with all applicable animal welfare laws.
The investigator shall make all efforts to prevent the repetition of any study resulting from inadequate planning, inappropriate species or diet, disease, or other environmental variables.
Refinements to such tests as the limit test, up-down test, low-volume test, or range finding should be used when appropriate. Skin testing should precede eye testing in order to guide the approach to (or necessity of) eye testing.
A proactive effort should be made to develop and validate alternative tests designed to reduce, replace, or refine animal testing.
11190 Sunrise Valley Drive,
Suite 300, Reston, VA 20191
stp@toxpath.org
703-438-7508
To anonymously report suspected criminal activity or illegal or unethical conduct by an STP member, management staff, or participant in any STP activity or STP business relationship, call the Navex toll-free fraud hotline at 800-826-6762.
Policies and Disclaimers
Copyright © 2020 The Society of Toxicologic Pathology. All rights reserved.
Scroll
